ptotoday.com 2018-10-20

# Privacy Policy

Effective June 15, 2013

School Family Media, Inc., the owner of this PTOtoday.com website, has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website, PTOtoday.com, as well as for our affiliated website: SchoolFamilyNights.com

#### **IP Addresses and Cookies**

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site.

#### **Data We Collect**

School Family Media collects or may collect information from our users at several different points on our website. School Family Media is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways other than as disclosed in this statement.

At various pages and in various processes on the site we require users to give us personal contact information (like their name and email address) and demographic information (like their zip code or school name) and general information about their school's parent group ("date elections held", for example). We use contact information to send the user information about our company and our partners and affiliates when requested to do so. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary and to help us understand your preferences, so we can personalize and continually improve your online experience. When a particular program of ours is associated with a specific partner (like one of our School Family Night options or our PTO Expos), contact information of users signing up for those programs may be shared with that specific partner. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

School Family media also collects from users and from schools information regarding their parent group (PTO or PTA, etc.) and their parent group activities. This information is fundamentally different than personal contact information, and we use this information in a variety of ways and with a variety of partners to provide the best service and offers that we can to school parent-teacher groups.

#### Methods of Gathering Information

**Information from you**  
This information comes directly from what you enter during registration on PTOtoday.com. The information you provide is used for sending you communication from our team and our partners and affiliates according to your personal preferences. You also have easy access to expanded PTOtoday.com services, which adds value and convenience to your user experience.

**Data Gathering from Publicly Available Sources**  
Many times, school parent-teacher group information (rosters and activities, for example) is available freely on school websites and similar publicly-shared venues. At times and in an effort to serve parent-teacher group leaders as well as possible, we will add information from these publicly available sites to our PTO Today database. This data is treated in the same way as lists that are entered directly from users of our site.

**Cookies**  
School Family Media may deposit cookies on users' hard drives. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. By setting a cookie on our site, a user may be able to enjoy an improved user experience on the site. Users who reject the cookie may still use PTOtoday.com, but they may be limited in some areas of our site.

Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance their experience. Some of the information about how our users experience our site, such as page views and specific pages visited, is logged by a third-party software program using cookies and Web beacons. Web beacons help us understand information such as what browsers our users have so that we are able to develop our site to best support our users.

You can opt-out of cookie placement at the browser level (see tools or options in your browser) or you can use the NAI Opt-out Tool.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Notification of Changes**  
As we continue to develop our website, this privacy policy most likely will change. We will post all changes to this policy on this page and will indicate at the top of this page the policy's effective date. We therefore encourage you to refer to this policy on an ongoing basis so that you understand our current privacy policy.

#### A Notice About Our Advertisers, Sponsors and Clients

School Family Media occasionally allows advertising or sponsorship links by partner organizations. School Family Media does not control linking practices of advertisers or sponsors and does not monitor or claim responsibility for any content or privacy practices of such websites. Once you have clicked on an advertisement and have left the PTOtoday.com website, you must read the privacy policy of the advertiser or sponsor to see how your personal information will be handled.

School Family Media may offer contests, sweepstakes, and promotions that are sponsored by third-party advertisers or sponsors. These third parties may obtain personally identifiable information that visitors voluntarily submit to participate in the activity. School Family Media does not control use of information by third parties.

As part of our service to school parent-teacher groups (PTOs and PTAs, etc.) and as part of our business offerings to select third-party clients, PTO Today may make aggregated educational data available to clients offering relevant programs to school parent groups. All client use of PTO Today data must be pre-approved and strictly limited. PTOtoday.com users can opt-out of inclusion in our educational data offerings using our contact and opt-out methods listed below.

School Family Media may use an advertising server developed by a third party to display ads on our site. Some of these ads may contain cookies that are set by third parties (advertisers, sponsors). We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they contain. The SchoolFamily.com privacy policy does not cover any use of information that a third-party ad server may have collected from you.

#### A Notice About External Links

Often, you will find links from PTOtoday.com to independently owned, controlled, and/or managed websites whose content we believe will be of possible interest and value to our visitors. Additionally, you'll see links from advertisers, sponsors, and other partners that may use PTOtoday's logo, School Family Media's corporate logo, or School Family Media branding as part of a co-branding agreement.

In many cases, these links represent cooperative projects or mutual links established with the organizations connected with these sites. We don't control the content of these links. These other sites may send you their own cookies, collect data, or solicit personal information. While we identify sponsor and advertiser areas of our websites, we do not control these cookies or the content of these third parties.

School Family Media has partnered with other companies to provide certain services. In some cases, you may see School Family Media's logo on another company's site.

Once you leave our servers (you can generally tell where you are by checking the URL in the location bar on your browser), the use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. That policy may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of any of these sites via a link from that site's home page, you should contact the site directly for more information.

We specifically recommend that parents or teachers monitor any new sites before children connect to them.

#### Our Commitment to Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, School Family Media does not knowingly collect or maintain personal information through the website from persons younger than 13 years of age, and no part of our website is directed to persons younger than 13. If you are younger than 13 years of age, then please do not use or access the website at any time or in any manner. If School Family Media learns that personally identifiable information of persons younger than 13 years of age has been collected through the website without verified parental consent, then School Family Media will take the appropriate steps to delete this information.

#### Choice/Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor.

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.

  1. You can send email to [info@ptotoday.com](mailto:info@ptotoday.com)
  2. You can call the following telephone number: 1-800-644-3561 X208

#### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact

PTO Today  
100 Stonewall Blvd, Suite 3  
Wrentham, MA 02093
